♪ In the face of turbulence ♪
♪ 面对动荡 ♪
♪ Your roots are firm ♪
♪ 你的根很牢固 ♪
♪ To this piece of land ♪
♪ 来到这片土地 ♪
♪ Chasing the flow of the waves ♪
♪ 追逐海浪的流动 ♪
♪ The fallen leaves ♪
♪ 落叶 ♪
♪ The horizon ♪
♪ 地平线 ♪
♪ Split Away ♪
♪ 分开 ♪
♪ At the end of the world ♪
♪ 在世界的尽头 ♪
♪ It's forever ♪
♪ 永远都是这样 ♪
♪ When we met and parted ♪
♪ 当我们相遇又分离 ♪
♪ When we depend on each other ♪ ♪ and we move away ♪
♪ 当我们互相依赖时 ♪ ♪ 然后我们就离开了 ♪
♪ I never forgot ♪
♪ 我从未忘记 ♪
♪ I cross the edge of the sword ♪
♪ 我跨过剑锋 ♪
♪ Crossing the starry sky ♪
♪ 穿越星空 ♪
♪ Falling dreams ♪
♪ 坠落的梦想 ♪
♪ Walk with me to tell the story of the wind ♪
♪ 与我同行，讲述风的故事 ♪
♪ The wind blows its waves ♪
♪ 风吹起波浪 ♪
♪ I see the thousands of candles cross ♪
♪ 我看到成千上万的蜡烛交叉 ♪
♪ The vast land and the boundless sea ♪
♪ 辽阔的土地和无边的海洋 ♪
♪ Red clothes flying high ♪
♪ 红衣飞得很高 ♪
♪ In the face of bitterness, sadness ♪ ♪ Emotion and happy adventure ♪
♪ 面对苦涩、悲伤 ♪ ♪ 情感和快乐的冒险 ♪
♪ I just hope you're by my side ♪
♪ 我只希望你在我身边 ♪
♪ I just want you to be by my side ♪
♪ 我只想你在我身边 ♪
♪ Like an interconnected tower ♪ ♪ I will accompany you until the end ♪
♪ 就像一座相连的塔 ♪ ♪ 我会陪你直到最后 ♪
♪ Seeing the fireflies that fill our shoulders ♪ ♪ On our shoulders ♪
♪ 看到萤火虫充满我们的肩膀 ♪ ♪ 在我们的肩膀上 ♪
♪ I don't regret it, I have no doubts ♪
♪ 我不后悔，我毫不怀疑 ♪
= Wonderland of Love =
= 爱的仙境 =
= Episode 17 =
=第17集=
Let's go.
我们走吧。
You still haven't recovered.
你还没有康复。
So don't drink anymore.
所以不要再喝酒了。
When I think about it,
当我想到这一点时，
when I think
当我想
in Tai Qing Palace.
in Tai Qing Palace.
It must be.
一定是。
Ying,
英，
Are you still mad at me?
你还生我的气吗？
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
They fought.
他们吵过架。
It's just a love fight.
这只是一场爱情斗争。
They will reconcile after the fight.
吵架后他们会和解的。
And also,
并且，
even if they fight,
即使他们打架，
seu Sr.shiqi
seu Sr.shiqi
really lose?
真的输了吗？
Let's not bother them.
我们不要打扰他们。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Where will we go?
我们要去哪里？
I'm a little hungry.
我有点饿了。
Why don't we go
我们为什么不去
at Tang convenience store?
唐便利店？
I always heard
我总是听到
that their snacks
他们的零食
famous in Dongdu.
闻名于东都。
Must be delicious.
一定很好吃。
I want to go try it.
我想去尝试一下。
Come, I'll take you.
来吧，我带你去。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Have your fingers improved?
你的手指有改善吗？
The chess pieces are ready.
棋子已经准备好了。
My fingers will recover.
我的手指会康复的。
You made a whole set of chess pieces
你做了一整套棋子
for your lord.
为了你的主。
You even ignored
你甚至忽略了
your fingers hurt.
你的手指受伤了。
But you never did
但你从来没有这样做过
for me.
为我。
Who said I never did anything for you?
谁说我从来没有为你做过任何事？
What did you do for me?
你为我做了什么？
Yourself
你自己
Did you do it?
你做了吗？
When I was at Tong Pass,
我在潼关的时候
I did this when I was at Tong Pass.
我在通关的时候就这么做过。
I wanted to find an opportunity
我想找个机会
to give you
为你带来
But then I discovered
但后来我发现
you are an ungrateful person
你是一个忘恩负义的人
nor does it help those in need.
也无法帮助那些有需要的人。
I better burn.
我最好烧掉。
You can't burn.
你不能燃烧。
If you're not angry...
如果你不生气的话...
If you're not angry,
如果你不生气的话
even if you scolded me
就算你骂我
Countless times a day,
一天无数次，
I'm going to listen.
我去听听。
Who will scold you?
谁会骂你？
I'll put it up for you to see.
我把它贴出来给你看看。
It's hard to do with one hand.
用一只手很难做到。
Can you help me?
你能帮助我吗？
It's not tight enough.
还不够紧。
Look.
看。
Otherwise, you are giving away free for nothing.
否则，你就是白白赠送 。
Let me see.
让我看看。
No final,
没有最终，
We are enemies, not friends.
我们是敌人，不是朋友。
When we meet again
当我们再次见面时
and we meet again,
我们又见面了，
I fear that on the battlefield
我害怕在战场上
fight for our lives.
为我们的生命而战。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
Careful.
小心。
Where's the ear?
耳朵在哪里？
He's already passed out.
他已经昏过去了。
I pierced him a few more times.
我又刺了他几下。
He just woke up he won't wake up.
他才刚醒， 就醒不来了。
It's really cruel.
实在是太残忍了。
He taught me well.
他教我很好。
Excuse me sir.
对不起，先生。
Lord, take us to the other side.
主啊，请带我们到彼岸。
The faster the better.
越快越好。
Press.
按。
Lord Qin?
秦王爷？
Are you calling me?
你在打电话给我吗？
Mister Qin, that was a great strategy.
秦先生，这真是一个好策略。
I was just planning.
我只是在计划。
When I saw the recipe that Taozi
当我看到桃子的菜谱时
taozi gave it to Chang 'er that day,
那天桃子送给嫦儿，
I had already suspected something.
我已经怀疑了一些事情。
As I already suspected,
正如我已经怀疑的那样，
you not only made contact
你不仅联系了
with the Cui army through the pharmacy,
与崔军 经过药铺，
and even acted.
甚至行动了。
Everything to make Chang'er believe
一切都是为了让嫦儿相信
Taozi spoke well of me.
桃子对我说得很好。
You have been persuaded.
你已经被说服了。
It was just to arrange a meal
本来只是为了安排一顿饭
to sting me and run away.
蜇我然后逃跑。
So you always knew
所以你一直都知道
you always accompanied us.
你一直陪伴着我们。
I know you well.
我很了解你。
If I didn't let you try to escape,
如果我不让你尝试逃跑
How would you be happy?
你会怎样幸福呢？
He is well.
他很好。
I'll take you back
我会带你回去
to your house.
去你家。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Governor,
州长，
the envoy we sent to Cui's army
我们派往崔军的使者
was whipped by Cui Yi
被崔毅鞭打
before being sent back here.
在被送回这里之前。
Cuiyi's temperament
翠衣的气质
still the same.
还是一样。
The vanguard of the Cui Army
崔军先锋
arrived at the entrance of Jiuqu.
到了九曲入口。
It looks like they want to cross the river.
看起来他们想要过河。
If Cui Yi cross or river
若翠衣渡或河
to besiege and attack Xichang,
围攻西昌，
there will be riots in the capital
首都将发生骚乱
I'm afraid it could disrupt the overall situation.
恐怕会扰乱 大局。
Governor,
州长，
Don't you think we should while they were crossing
你不认为我们应该 在他们过境时
cross the river.
过河。
Cuyi has always been cunning.
楚易一向很狡猾。
If he had the courage to cross the river at the entrance to Jiuqu,
如果他有勇气 在九曲入口处过河，
he must have considered
他一定考虑过
Shallow waters.
浅水（区。
It's easy to cross the river,
过河很容易
no,
不，
he will not cross the river
他不会过河
will not cross the river.
不会过河。
He must be diverting attention.
他一定是在转移注意力。
Could it be that Cui Yi's son
难道是崔毅的儿子？
Wasn't he intercepted and killed?
不是被拦截杀了吗？
It seems this time
看来这次
his goal is not Xichang.
他的目标不是西昌。
Let's let him cross the river.
我们让他过河吧。
Mayor,
市长，
If the Cui army crosses the river and helps Li Ni...
如果崔军渡河 帮助李泥……
I said let him cross the river.
我说让他过河吧。
If he dares to attack Xichang
如果他敢攻打西昌
to attack Xichang
攻打西昌
and fight him to the death.
并与他决一死战。
He is heading to Luoyang,
他要去洛阳，
I will send troops
我将派遣军队
to seize the opportunity li Ni.
李妮抓住机会 。
Be careful, it's hot.
小心点，很热。
Taozi,
Taozi,
How is Lieutenant He's health?
何中尉的健康状况如何？
Do you need medicinal herbs?
您需要草药吗？
I'm glad Your Highness
我很高兴殿下
we have no shortage of medicinal herbs,
我们不缺药材，
I believe you know
我相信你知道
of your provocation
你的挑衅
made Lieutenant He's illness worse.
使得何中尉的病情更加严重。
How bad.
多么糟糕。
How about I say something
我说句话怎么样
to keep her alive.
让她活着。
After this lesson,
听完这节课后，
I sent several heavy troops
我派了几支重兵
to surround the Tai Qing Palace inside and outside the palace,
将太清宫围 在宫内宫外，
out and in.
出入。
I also sent dozens of observers
我还派了几十名观察员
to watch each exit.
观察每个出口。
If you still want to escape,
如果你还想逃的话
I will be nervous for you.
我会为你紧张。
Mr Qin,
Mr Qin,
I believe you already planned everything
我相信你已经计划好了一切
for a safe attack
为了安全攻击
em Xichang.
em Xichang.
No matter how complete the plan is,
无论计划多么完整，
there will be failures.
会有失败。
How can we talk about being thorough
怎样才能谈得彻底
or ensure certain success?
或确保一定的成功？
Since we don't have a complete plan,
由于我们还没有一个完整的计划，
how about that?
那个怎么样？
I'll do it for you,
我会为你做的，
after killing Sun Jing,
杀死孙靖后，
and you let me go.
然后你让我走了。
Then,
然后，
not worth it.
不值得。
So it's not worth it.
所以这是不值得的。
I didn't imagine that
我没想到
that you gave me so much value.
你给了我如此多的价值。
A woman like me
像我这样的女人
worth more than Sun Jin?
比孙晋还值钱？
Cui Yi's only daughter
崔毅唯一的女儿
It is naturally more valuable than Sun Jin.
自然比孙晋更值钱。
So you already knew she was the general's daughter?
所以你已经知道 她是将军的女儿了？
So you already know.
所以你已经知道了。
It's no wonder that
这也难怪
you won't let me go.
你不会让我走的。
Miss Taozi,
Miss Taozi,
Can you go out for a bit?
你能出去一下吗？
I have some words
我有几句话
to say
说
to Lieutenant He.
给何中尉。
In fact, after saving you,
其实救了你之后，
I wrote a letter
我写了一封信
for General Cui.
为崔将军。
General Cui
崔将军
it turns out we were close we were close by.
事实证明我们就 在附近。
It's a shame we arrived late
可惜我们来晚了
and Mr. Cui fell into the river.
崔先生掉进了河里。
But now that we've rescued Ying,
但既然我们已经救了莹
don't worry.
不用担心。
Ying is safe.
莹安全了。
He is recovering in Zhenxi barracks.
他正在 镇西军营康复。
I sincerely hope you can lead your army
我真诚地希望 你能带领你的军队
to join Zhenxi, capture Xichang together,
to join Zhenxi, capture Xichang together,
to finish off Sun Jin. To suppress the rebellion.
来解决孙进。 去镇压叛乱。
Until then, your pearl in the palm of your hand
到那时，你的掌上明珠
your pearl in the palm of your hand.
你的掌上明珠。
I told you you're fine.
我告诉过你你很好。
I sincerely beg him
我真诚地恳求他
join me in suppressing the Crook Sun
和我一起镇压克鲁克太阳
and recover Xichang.
并收复西昌。
Although General Cui responded to my letter,
虽然崔将军 回复了我的信，
but...
但...
What do you mean, Your Highness?
殿下，您这是什么意思？
Be honest.
说实话。
I finally discovered
我终于发现
the heroine who led women to fight fought to the death in Yingzhou
带领妇女奋战的女英雄 在颍州奋战到底
your mother
你的母亲
And his mother.
还有他的母亲。
Heroica's surname is He.
海罗卡的姓氏是何。
So you changed your last name
所以你改变了你的姓氏
and say that he belongs to the He clan.
并说他是何氏的。
These days, these days.
这些天， 这些天。
The heroine is such a brave figure.
女主角就是这样一个勇敢的人物。
General Cui is also extraordinary
崔将军 也是不凡
have a daughter like you.
有一个像你这样的女儿。
Are you investigating?
你在调查吗？
Sim.
西姆。
I do not know anything
我什么都不知道
about Great General Cui.
关于崔大将军。
So I can only ask for this method.
所以只能求这个方法了。
Perhaps
也许
after some time,
一段时间后，
you will know what kind of person
你就会知道什么样的人
my father.
我的父亲。
I have a bad feeling about this.
我对此有一种不好的预感。
Why?
为什么？
I always feel that
我总觉得
that he is like you.
他和你一样。
Intelligent,
聪明的，
and extremely powerful.
并且极其强大。
I don't know how he will react
我不知道他会作何反应
how he will react.
他会如何反应。
I am my father's only daughter.
我是我父亲唯一的女儿。
You used me to pressure you.
你利用我来给你施加压力。
I need to tell you
我需要告诉你
How will he react?
他会有何反应？
If you fall into his hands,
如果你落入他的手中
It is likely that
可能就是这样
he will whip you.
他会鞭打你。
So I'll have to be careful
所以我必须要小心
don't fall into his hand.
不要落入他的手中。
Grande General,
大将军，
the vanguard has already crossed the river.
先头部队 已经过了河。
It's time for the middle army It's time to attack.
中军该 进攻了。
This mentor
这位导师
is hidden in Luoyang.
隐于洛阳。
And you dared to kill my son.
你还敢杀我儿子。
The Cui army
崔军
Will retaliate.
会报复。
Like this?
像这样？
Doesn't Cui Yi have a son?
崔毅不是有儿子吗？
Has a daughter?
有女儿吗？
Is Lieutenant He Cui Lin?
何翠林中尉？
The one who died
死去的那个人
Was it just a hoax?
这只是一个骗局吗？
It can not be.
它不可能是。
Absolutely impossible.
绝对不可能。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
you are lying to me
你在骗我
to lie to me
对我撒谎
so I can marry her?
这样我就可以娶她了？
Think carefully
仔细想想
Mr. Cui's attitude
崔先生的态度
com to Tenente He.
com 到他中尉。
Also, think about it
另外，想一下
if I want to deceive you.
如果我想欺骗你。
I understood.
我明白了。
That's why,
这就是为什么，
you kept her trapped
你让她被困住了
locked her
锁住了她
and sent a great army.
并派遣了一支强大的军队。
Do you want to use it to pressure Cuyi?
难道想用它 来给粗衣施压吗？
That's not pressuring him.
这并没有 给他压力。
Cui Yi,
Cui Yi,
para o grande general Pingliang, Cui Yi.
para o grande general Pingliang, Cui Yi.
To think about the Zhenxi army
想想镇西军
to save his daughter,
为了救女儿，
I asked him to join us
我邀请他加入我们
to calm the rebellion
平息叛乱
to recover Xichang.
收复西昌。
Come take the medicine.
快来吃药吧。
For you.
为你。
The flowers that Mister Qin sent today
今天秦先生送的花
they are so beautiful.
他们是如此美丽。
Because today
因为今天
different today?
今天不同吗？
How different?
有什么不同？
As if you had changed
仿佛你变了
like always.
像往常一样。
I'm just thinking
我只是在想
that in some days,
在某些日子里，
maybe I can
也许我可以
to my father's side.
到我父亲身边。
If I don't get well,
如果我身体不好的话
Won't he be more worried?
他不会更担心吗？
Have you thought of a way out of here?
你有没有想过离开这里的办法？
I think our father once led the army
我想我们的父亲 曾经领导过军队
and arrived outside of Luoyang.
到了洛阳城外。
The situation is changing rapidly.
情况正在迅速变化。
Li Ni
李妮
You won't be able to keep us for long.
你不可能留住我们太久的。
That is great.
太棒了。
I was just thinking
我只是在想
if the Young Master
如果少爷
escape safely,
安全逃脱，
it would be really good.
那就太好了。
Otherwise,
否则，
I will regret it forever.
我会后悔一辈子的。
Don't be sad.
别伤心。
If Young Master knew,
如果少爷知道的话，
I would also expect that
我也希望
Don't you think too much,
你别想太多
to take care of yourself.
照顾好自己。
The living must cherish their lives.
活着的人一定要珍惜自己的生命。
It's the greatest comfort
这是最大的安慰
for the deceased.
为了死者。
That's what my father told me
这是我父亲告诉我的
the mother sacrificed herself for the city.
母亲 为了这座城市牺牲了自己。
Mister shiqi, there is news. Sun Jing actually mobilized his troops.
十七先生，有消息了。 孙敬竟然调动了兵力。
And divided them in two.
并将他们一分为二。
One heads to Luoyang,
一人前往洛阳，
and the other goes straight to the main camp.
另一个则直奔 主营。
Exactly as you predicted.
正如你所预测的那样。
That scoundrel Sun Jing
孙靖那个混蛋
is enjoying
正在享受
o ataque de Cui Yi a Luoyang
o ataque de Cui Yi a Luoyang
to send troops to attack the Zhenxi army.
出兵 攻打镇西军。
And sent troops
并派出军队
for our family.
为了我们的家人。
It seems like he really wants to seize the opportunity.
看来他是真的想 抓住这个机会。
So we'll attack them here first, and catch them off guard.
所以我们就先在这里攻击他们， 打他们一个措手不及。
The weather is getting cold now.
现在天气变冷了。
Where did these flowers come from?
这些花是从哪里来的？
Mr. Qin didn't send
秦先生没有发送
to send flowers every day?
每天送花吗？
So I took the petals
于是我拿起花瓣
and flower buds.
和花蕾。
Then, those that suit will be used
然后，将使用那些适合的
and the others can be used for bathing.
其他的可以用来洗澡。
No waste.
没有浪费。
Our Taozi
我们的桃子
doesn't care about problems.
不关心问题。
Stay here every day
每天都呆在这里
It's very boring.
很无聊。
We have to find something to do.
我们必须找点事做。
Before Mr Qin sent by Mr Qin
秦先生发送之前
They are really cool.
他们真的很酷。
Mr He,
何先生，
I think that
我觉得
you look very good
你看起来很好
like this.
像这样。
Do you really like that
你真的喜欢那样吗
like such a beautiful girl.
像这样一个美丽的女孩。
But, Lieutenant He,
但是，何中尉，
You look brave too.
你看起来 也很勇敢。
But you don't dress like that
但你不穿成这样
every day.
每天。
I still think you
我还是觉得你
The most beautiful.
最美丽的。
Why hasn't Mister Qin arrived yet?
秦先生怎么还没来？
I think
我认为
he must have been
他一定是
for something.
为了某件事。
Perhaps
也许
My father has already arrived.
我父亲已经到了。
Luoyang City really needs to step up.
洛阳市确实需要加强。
Every moment that lasts is a moment gained.
每一个持续的时刻 都是一个获得的时刻。
Se Luoyang cair,
Se Luoyang cair,
Sun Jing's forces
孙靖的势力
they will soon join them,
他们很快就会加入他们的行列，
joining them.
加入他们。
If that happen,
如果发生这种情况，
it will be a problem.
这将是一个问题。
Youdao,
Youdao,
let's make a bet.
我们打个赌吧。
What?
什么？
Let's bet on how long
我们来赌一下要多久
luoyang can last.
luoyang can last.
I won't bet with you.
我不会和你打赌。
Temoque a Luoyang
Temoque a Luoyang
may not last long.
可能不会持续太久。
What a bunch of idiots.
真是一群白痴啊。
We can only wait
我们只能等待
cui Yi possa atrasar a Sun Jing.
cui Yi possa atrasar a Sun Jing.
Serious?
严肃的？
The Great General is here.
大将军来了。
It's a guess.
这是一个猜测。
But it is quite possible.
但这是很有可能的。
During these years, the Cui Army in the name of the prince,
这些年，崔军 以太子之名，
in the name of the Young Master.
以少爷之名。
My father is in Yingzhou in Yingzhou.
我父亲在颍州颍 州。
But every time he acts,
但他每次表演的时候，
he crushes Sun Jing's army.
他粉碎了孙敬的军队。
Li Ni is very cunning.
李妮非常狡猾。
He can't understand
他无法理解
the father's method.
父亲的方法。
So he won't do anything reckless.
所以他不会做出鲁莽的事情。
What does Lord Qin want to do?
秦王到底想做什么？
He wants to go to war wants to go to war?
他想要开战 想要开战？
Let's attack the enemy
让我们攻击敌人吧
and then fight the enemy.
然后与敌人战斗。
At Li Ni's priority
李妮优先
It's winning over the father.
这是战胜了父亲。
To form an alliance,
为了结成联盟，
recover Xichang,
recover Xichang,
and protect the Li family kingdom.
并保护李家王国。
Li Ni
李妮
He's very arrogant.
他非常傲慢。
Miss,
错过，
do not say anything.
不要说什么。
When the general comes,
当将军到来时，
we have to hit him
我们必须打他
to vent our frustration.
来发泄我们的不满。
Don't worry,
不用担心，
I won't say anything to him.
我不会对他说什么。
And also,
并且，
when my father is a notable figure,
当我的父亲是一位著名人物时
when my father is a notable figure?
当我的父亲是一个著名人物时？
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
our prisoners are housed.
我们的囚犯得到了安置。
Some injured soldiers
一些受伤的士兵
were also treated.
也受到了治疗。
This battle
这场战斗
made our some victims to Sun Jing.
给孙静造成了我们的一些牺牲品。
Sr. shiqi.
Sr. shiqi.
(Fengtai Gate)
(Fengtai Gate)
Stormed the Fengtai Gate at around 3pm.
下午3点左右攻入丰台门。
No news yet
还没有消息
of Lord Xin, Lord Qi and the Emperor.
辛君、齐君、皇帝。
Furthermore,
此外，
Cui Yi also sent someone to send a letter.
崔毅也派人 送信。
I am serving His Majesty, Lord Xin and Mr. Qi in Luoyang.
我 在洛阳侍奉辛王陛下和齐先生。
To show my sincerity,
为了表达我的诚意，
to show my sincerity. From the Cui Army.
以表达我的诚意。 出自崔军。
If not, we will see you in battle.
如果没有， 我们会在战斗中见到你。
Like father, like daughter.
有其父必有其女。
They refuse to suffer any losses.
他们拒绝承受任何损失。
Your Highness,
殿下，
please have some tea.
请喝点茶。
For you.
为你。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Are you still using the device?
您还在使用该设备吗？
Sim.
西姆。
The silver needle to remove the silver needle.
银针 取出银针。
After that,
在那之后，
I never took it off again.
我再也没有把它摘下来。
You even only have one device.
您甚至只有一台设备。
Your Highness, why are you acting like this?
殿下， 您为何如此？
If anyone wants to give me another one,
如果有人想再 给我一份
I don't mind accepting.
我不介意接受。
Despise your busy military affairs,
鄙视你繁忙的军务，
you came here.
你来过这里。
My father must have
我父亲一定有
He has already shown you his sincerity.
他已经向你表明了他的诚意。
Before,
前，
I was curious
我很好奇
your personality.
你的个性。
He is exactly as I imagined.
他和我想象的一模一样。
You two
你们俩
are almost the same.
几乎是一样的。
You really are his daughter.
你确实是他的女儿。
And he is your father.
他是你的父亲。
Like this?
像这样？
Your father
你的父亲
captured effortlessly
毫不费力地捕捉到
without major difficulties.
没有重大困难。
My father and my two older brothers
我的父亲和我的两个哥哥
were captured by their father.
被他们的父亲俘虏了。
My father is generous and courteous.
我的父亲为人慷慨、彬彬有礼。
I believe the emperor
我相信皇帝
will thank you very much.
会非常感谢你的。
So tell me,
所以告诉我，
your face is so beautiful.
你的脸是如此美丽。
You look more like dad
你看起来更像爸爸
or your mother?
或者你的母亲？
I hope you don't think that
我希望你不要这么想
that these sweet words
这些甜言蜜语
will make me forget
会让我忘记
of his prison.
他的监狱。
Your father is so generous.
你父亲真慷慨。
I dare not force you to stay any longer.
我不敢再强留你了。
It's just...
只是...
Who knows when and where it will be
谁知道它会在何时何地发生
the next time we meet.
下次我们见面的时候。
When you go
当你去
let me go?
让我走？
Great General Cui wrote a letter
崔大将军 写信
He wants to see you tomorrow.
他想明天见你。
How could I not agree?
我怎么能不同意呢？
Tomorrow?
明天？
It's too early, isn't it?
还太早了，不是吗？
Give it time.
给它时间。
Did you really do that?
你真的这么做了吗？
Can you really hear?
你真的能听到吗？
From now on, as long as you blow,
从此以后，只要你吹，
I will find you immediately.
我会立即找到你。
I am here.
我在这里。
What...
什么...
What it was?
这是什么？
Not satisfied?
不满意？
I really like.
我很喜欢。
I just want to eat some pig ear.
我只是想吃点猪耳朵。
I'll buy it for you.
我给你买。
Don't be sad,
别伤心，
I will be back soon.
我会很快回来。
What it was?
这是什么？
Tomorrow I'm leaving.
明天我就要走了。
Will you really
你真的会吗
buy pig ears?
买猪耳朵吗？
But...
但...
You said you wanted to eat.
你说你想吃东西。
You really are
你真的是
really so stupid.
真的好傻。
I am here.
我在这里。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
you didn't say that
你没这么说
the army is heavy
军队很重
and many observers are watching here?
还有很多观察家 在这里观看？
Sim.
西姆。
Then,
然后，
if we leave here in silence,
如果我们默默地离开这里
Will anyone notice?
有人会注意到吗？
We will try.
我们会尝试。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Let's see who gets to the stable first.
让我们看看谁先到达马厩。
He is well.
他很好。
♪ In this turbulence ♪
♪ 在这动荡之中 ♪
♪ Your roots are firm ♪ ♪ On this piece of land ♪
♪ 你的根很牢固 ♪ ♪ 在这片土地上 ♪
♪ Chasing the waves ♪
♪ 追逐海浪 ♪
♪ Leaves flutter on the horizon ♪
♪ 树叶在地平线上飘扬 ♪
♪ Looking away ♪
♪ 移开视线 ♪
♪ The end of the world is eternity ♪
♪ 世界的终结就是永恒 ♪
Who's there?
谁在那儿？
♪ When we depend on each other ♪ ♪ and we move away ♪
♪ 当我们互相依赖时 ♪ ♪ 然后我们就离开了 ♪
- Your Highness. -His highness.
- 殿下。 -殿下。
♪ The wind blows the cut swords ♪
♪ 风吹动斩断的剑 ♪
♪ Crossing the starry sky ♪
♪ 穿越星空 ♪
♪ The dream falls and scatters in the wind ♪
♪ 梦落下，随风飘散 ♪
You lost.
你输了。
♪ The wind blows the waves ♪
♪ 风吹起波浪 ♪
♪ I see thousands of sails crossing each other ♪ The vast land and the vast sea ♪
♪ 我看到万帆交错 ♪ 广阔的土地和广阔的海洋 ♪
♪ Red clothes flying high ♪
♪ 红衣飞得很高 ♪
I don't know who it will be
我不知道会是谁
The winner in this case.
在这种情况下，获胜者。
So let's keep playing.
所以我们继续玩吧。
To see who gets to Wonderland first.
看看谁先到达仙境。
♪ Like a lightning bolt of a tree ♪ With interconnected roots ♪
♪ 就像树上的一道闪电 ♪ 根部相连 ♪
♪ I will accompany you until the end ♪
♪ 我会陪你到最后 ♪
♪ Facing wind and rain together ♪ With a happy smile ♪
♪ 一起面对风雨 ♪ 带着幸福的微笑 ♪
♪ I don't regret it, I have no doubts ♪
♪ 我不后悔，我毫不怀疑 ♪
♪ The old road at sunset ♪
♪ 夕阳下的老路 ♪
♪ I will accompany you until the end ♪
♪ 我会陪你到最后 ♪
♪ Seeing the fireflies that fill our shoulders ♪ ♪ On our shoulders ♪
♪ 看到萤火虫充满我们的肩膀 ♪ ♪ 在我们的肩膀上 ♪
♪ I don't regret it, I have no doubts ♪
♪ 我不后悔，我毫不怀疑 ♪
Look at the capital of Wonderland
看看仙境之都
It's really beautiful.
真的很漂亮。
Look.
看。
I always wanted to know
我一直想知道
How did you discover my identity?
你是怎么发现我的身份的？
Miss behavior
错过行为
not an ordinary person can understand.
不是一般人 能够理解的。
No one ever suspected
没有人怀疑过
my identity and my relationship
我的身份和我的关系
with Young Master before.
之前和少爷。
Because you
因为你
Did you undersand?
你明白了吗？
When you lied to me
当你对我撒谎时
being Mr. Cui's concubine,
作为崔先生的小妾，
I began to suspect his identity.
我开始怀疑 他的身份。
So I organized a banquet
于是我举办了一场宴会
to test Mr Cui.
来考验崔先生。
This only confirms
这只能证实
his identity was not simple.
他的身份不简单。
You and your young master seemed to be lord and servant.
你和你少爷 就像是主仆一样。
But in reality
但现实中
he treated her with even more respect.
他对她更加尊重。
And before what happened in Luoyang,
而在洛阳发生那件事之前，
I saw you intrude in your Master's place.
我看到你闯入 了你主人的住所。
I knew that
我知道
after removing my mask,
摘下面具后
after removing my mask.
摘下面具后。
But at that moment,
但就在那一刻，
I was just defending in battle.
我只是 在战斗中防守。
How can you be sure
你怎么能确定
that I was my father's daughter?
我是我父亲的女儿？
When you were at Tong Pass,
当你在潼关的时候，
risked his life
冒着生命危险
to save General Cui
救崔将军
It may seem perfect to others.
对于其他人来说，这可能看起来很完美。
But after thinking about it,
但转念一想之后，
something seems to be wrong.
似乎有些不对劲。
I finally guessed it.
我终于猜到了。
So you always knew.
所以你一直都知道。
You know what?
你知道吗？
I always wonder
我总是想知道
If you are not from the Cui family,
如果你不是 崔家的人，
and I am not from the Li family.
而且我也不是李家的人。
There will be
将有
Between us between us?
我们之间 我们之间？
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
the identity is accurate.
身份准确。
There is nothing that
没有什么是
we can not do anything.
我们无能为力。
You are sure.
你确定。
When the chaos began,
当混乱开始时，
I found this turbulent world
我发现了这个动荡的世界
there was no salvation.
没有拯救。
I couldn't see the people's sadness
我看不到 人们的悲伤
for the people.
为了人民。
So I asked dad
于是我问爸爸
let me and the prince
让我和王子
south with our army.
随我军南下。
Just in time,
恰逢其时，
it was just for
这只是为了
restore peace to the world.
恢复世界和平。
But I didn't expect that
但我没想到的是
to the Li family
致李家
There was someone like you.
有一个像你一样的人。
When we meet,
当我们见面时，
Did I cause you a lot of trouble?
我给你添了很多麻烦吗？
Well, me too.
嗯，我也是。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
Did you think
你觉得
if some day
如果有一天
can restore peace
可以恢复和平
and peace for the world.
以及世界的和平。
Then,
然后，
What kind of king does the world need?
世界需要什么样的国王？
Your father is already old.
你父亲已经老了。
O Lorde Xin eo Lorde Qi
O Lorde Xin eo Lorde Qi
They are not good rulers.
他们不是好的统治者。
We still have the emperor's great-grandson.
我们还有 皇帝的曾孙。
I want to find him back
我想把他找回来
to ask the father
去问父亲
to name him crown prince.
封他为太子。
He has excellent intelligence,
他有着出色的智力，
and exceptional mentors.
和杰出的导师。
He definitely
他绝对
he will definitely become a good king.
他一定会成为一个好国王。
And if you can't find the imperial great-grandson,
如果找不到 皇曾孙，
or if your father
或者如果你的父亲
don't want to name it
不想说出它的名字
to be the prince?
成为王子？
Let's run away.
让我们逃跑。
The world is at peace.
世界太平了。
And the emperor's great-grandson has already been found.
而皇帝的曾孙也 已经找到了。
Let's leave Xichang
离开西昌吧
to live freely in Laolan Pass.
在老兰关自由自在地生活。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
Even though I know it's not true,
尽管我知道这不是真的
hear you say that
听到你这么说
makes me happy.
让我开心。
That day we agreed
那天我们约定
Let's go for a walk through Wonderland
我们去仙境散步吧
and stroll through Wonderland.
漫步仙境。
It is a shame
这是一种耻辱
the world is still in chaos.
世界仍处于混乱之中。
Tomorrow,
明天，
everyone follows their own path.
每个人都走自己的路。
That day will come.
那一天将会到来。
By the time,
到......的时候，
First let's see Wonderland.
首先我们来看看仙境。
Then we go to Laolan Pass.
然后我们就去老兰关。
Let's ride a horse together,
我们一起去骑马吧
and appreciate the wonder of the world.
并欣赏世界的奇妙。
He is well?
他还好吗？
He is well.
他很好。
Tomorrow we will part.
明天我们就要分别了。
I don't know when we'll see each other again.
我不知道我们什么时候才能再次见面。
In that day,
在那一天，
I took what you love.
我拿走了你所爱的。
Today,
今天，
returned to the owner.
归还给主人。
Ying,
英，
you and your child
你和你的孩子
really grew up together?
真的是一起长大的吗？
I can see that you are particularly worried
我看得出你特别担心
with this subject.
与这个主题。
It is clear.
很明显。
When I first saw you two,
当我第一次见到你们两个时
you were so close.
你是如此接近。
It made me uncomfortable.
这让我很不舒服。
Why do you even want to ask?
为什么你还想问？
The Young Master
少爷
is probably no longer in this world.
大概已经不在这个世界上了。
I just wanted to hear
我只是想听听
hear you explain to me.
听你给我解释一下。
Then I won't have any suspicions.
那我就不会有任何怀疑了。
After this,
在这之后，
I won't ask anymore.
我不会再问了
Young Master's real name
少爷真实姓名
É Liu Chengfeng.
É Liu Chengfeng.
He saved me when I was young.
当我还小的时候，他救了我。
His parents died early.
他的父母很早就去世了。
That's why,
这就是为什么，
he was adopted by his father.
他被他的父亲收养。
When my mother was young,
我妈妈年轻的时候，
When he was young, it affected his health.
年轻时， 这影响了他的健康。
That's why after ten years of being married to my father,
这就是为什么在与我父亲结婚十年后
she never had children.
她从未生过孩子。
But at that time,
但当时，
his father was already a general on the border.
他的父亲已经是边境的将军了。
To control his father, the king insisted
为了控制他的父亲，国王坚持
to give him another wife
给他另一个妻子
to give him another wife.
给他另一个妻子。
Later, my mother was determined
后来妈妈就下定决心
to seek medical advice.
寻求医疗建议。
I was finally born.
我终于出生了。
It is a shame
这是一种耻辱
cannot satisfy the court.
无法令 法庭满意。
So my father lied to me saying that
所以我父亲对我撒谎说
he had a son
他有一个儿子
called Cui Lin, following tradition the Cui family gave its name,
名叫崔林，按照传统 崔氏家族的名字命名，
to report to the court.
向法院报告。
I understood.
我明白了。
Since then,
自那以后，
meu pai lutou em Yingzhou, em Yingzhou.
meu pai lutou em Yingzhou, em Yingzhou.
His mother fought with courage and died in the city.
他的母亲奋勇作战 ，死在城里。
The mother's position as the heroine.
母亲 作为女主角的地位。
The father enjoys the mother very much.
父亲 非常喜欢母亲。
And he never remarried.
而且他再也没有再婚。
Since then, my father
从此以后，我的父亲
raised me as a boy.
把我当作一个男孩抚养长大。
But when I turn seven,
但当我七岁的时候
I can no longer hide
我无法再隐藏
my feminine side.
我女性化的一面。
So my father asked Liu Chengfeng
于是父亲就问刘乘风
take my name, Cui Lin,
以我的名字，崔琳，
to hide
隐藏
to prevent my girl identity
防止我的女孩身份
be exposed.
被暴露。
Since little,
从小，
the Young Master faced many dangers
少爷面临重重危险
many dangers.
许多危险。
Nobody knows his name
没有人知道他的名字
nobody knew.
没有人知道。
Therefore, he became
因此，他成为
a shadow for me.
对我来说是一个影子。
We both grew up together.
我们俩一起长大。
I considered him like an older brother.
我把他当作一个哥哥。
Naturally, we were closer
自然而然，我们就更亲近了
than others.
相对于其它的。
You consider him an older brother,
你把他当作哥哥，
but he doesn't think so.
但他不这么认为。
He is no longer with us.
他不再和我们在一起了。
Why do you care so much about this?
你为什么这么关心这个？
Why does it always have to be about me?
为什么总是和我有关？
And you?
你呢？
And me?
和我？
Mr. Gu's daughter,
顾先生的女儿，
likes you a lot.
很喜欢你。
When we were in Xichang,
我们在西昌的时候，
she came to the inn to give him a message.
她来到客栈 是为了给他捎口信。
Won't you return her love?
你不会 回报她的爱吗？
What does Ms. GU feels about me what Ms. GU feels for me
顾女士对我有什么感觉
We're different.
我们不同。
She is interested in me.
她对我感兴趣。
But I have no interest in her.
但我对她没有兴趣。
So I can only disappoint her.
所以我只能让她失望了。
Drinking and singing together
一起喝酒唱歌
when we think about life.
当我们思考生活时。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
Can you sing a song for me?
你能为我唱首歌吗？
I don't know how to sing.
我不知道怎么唱歌。
I can only hum a little
我只能哼一声
to Laolan melody.
跟着老兰的旋律。
Laolan's melody is also good.
老兰的旋律也很好听。
I want to listen.
我想听。
These rural folk songs
这些乡村民谣
cannot be compared to the elegance of literature.
无法与文学的优雅相比。
It's a little rough.
有点粗糙。
So please be patient.
所以请耐心等待。
I don't mind.
我不介意。
He is well.
他很好。
♪ The Laolan River has eighteen bends ♪ The Laolan River has 18 bends.
♪ 老兰河有十八个弯 ♪ 老兰河有十八个弯。
♪ The first bend in the river is Yinsong ♪
♪ 河流的第一个弯是银松 ♪
♪ The fish in Yinsong is fat and heavy ♪
♪ 银松的鱼又肥又重 ♪
♪ But you can't compare ♪ The girl who opened the window.
♪ 但你无法比较 ♪ 打开窗户的女孩。
♪ The Laolan River has 18 bends ♪ ♪ The Laolan River has eighteen bends ♪
♪ 老兰河有十八个弯 ♪
Did I sing badly?
我唱得不好吗？
It's a little out of tune.
有点不协调。
So why did you ask me to sing?
那你为什么要请我唱歌？
But it sounds good.
但听起来不错。
Serious?
严肃的？
So I will sing seriously this time.
所以这次我会认真地唱歌。
He is well.
他很好。
Now I'm going to get up and sing seriously.
现在我要站起来认真地唱歌了。
♪ The Laolan River has 18 bends ♪ The Laolan River has 18 bends.
♪ 老兰河有十八个弯 ♪ 老兰河有十八个弯。
♪ The first bend in the river is Yinsong ♪
♪ 河流的第一个弯是银松 ♪
♪ The fish in Yinsong is fat and heavy ♪
♪ 银松的鱼又肥又重 ♪
♪ But they don't compare to that girl's beautiful eyes.
♪ 但它们无法 与那个女孩美丽的眼睛相比。
♪ The river bends are eighteen ♪ ♪ The Laolan River has 18 bends ♪
♪ 河道有十八个弯 ♪ ♪ 老兰河有十八个弯 ♪
♪ The second bend in the river is ♪ It's a beautiful coast.
♪ 河流的第二个拐弯是 ♪ 这是一个美丽的海岸。
Ying.
莹。
♪ Between the moonlight and your vows ♪
♪ 在月光和你的誓言之间 ♪
♪ To fall into my heart ♪
♪ 坠入我的心 ♪
♪ Telling me about your eternity ♪
♪ 告诉我你的永恒 ♪
If you don't wake up,
如果你不醒来
I go...
我去...
I'll kiss you.
我会吻你。
♪ Who can make me forget everything ♪
♪ 谁能让我忘记一切 ♪
I'm really going to kiss you.
我真的要吻你了。
♪ Tomorrow ♪
♪ 明天 ♪
♪ We search together ♪
♪ 我们一起寻找 ♪
♪ You took me ♪ Through the night.
♪ 你带着我 ♪ 度过了整个夜晚。
♪ The shattered world brings with it ♪
♪ 破碎的世界随之而来 ♪
♪ You gave me a firm conviction ♪
♪ 你给了我坚定的信念 ♪
(Lyrics) In adversity, the only light is love ♪ That never dies ♪
（歌词）在逆境中，唯一的光明就是爱 ♪永不消逝♪
♪ Every breakup I endured ♪
♪ 我忍受的每一次分手 ♪
♪ Waiting for you every second ♪ ♪ Every second I look for you ♪
♪ 每一秒都在等你 ♪ ♪ 每一秒都在寻找你 ♪
♪ I'm not afraid of obstacles ♪ ♪ I want to love until the end ♪
♪ 我不怕障碍 ♪ ♪ 我想爱到最后 ♪
♪ change ♪
♪ 改变 ♪
♪ Crossing the night ♪ ♪ I will cross the danger ♪
♪ 跨越黑夜 ♪ ♪ 我会跨越危险 ♪
♪ I make my heart burn with passion ♪
♪ 我的心因激情而燃烧 ♪
♪ You're by my side ♪
♪ 你在我身边 ♪
♪ Arranging towards our eternal vow ♪
♪ 为我们永恒的誓言而安排 ♪
♪ Growing up stubborn ♪ Can't accept it.
♪ 长大后固执 ♪ 无法接受。
♪ Passing through destiny, ♪ carrying persistence ♪
♪ 穿越命运 ♪ 承载着坚持 ♪
♪ And don't let go ♪ ♪ Standing by your side ♪
♪ 不要放手 ♪ ♪ 站在你身边 ♪
♪ In this suffering ♪ ♪ I finish painting the world in my hands ♪
♪ 在这痛苦中 ♪ ♪ 我完成了手中的世界 ♪
♪ To protect this eternal love ♪
♪ 为了守护这份永恒的爱 ♪
♪ Based on the faith you gave me ♪
♪ 基于你给我的信念 ♪
♪ I'm not afraid of obstacles or thorns ♪ We hold on until the end.
♪ 我不害怕障碍或荆棘 ♪ 我们坚持到最后。
♪ Going through the night with you ♪ By your side ♪
♪ 与你一起度过夜晚 ♪ 在你身边 ♪
♪ Taking care of our belief ♪
♪ 照顾我们的信仰 ♪
♪ Holding your hand ♪ ♪ I'm holding your hand until the end ♪
♪ 牵着你的手 ♪ ♪ 我会牵着你的手直到最后 ♪
♪ In defense of eternal love ♪
♪ 捍卫永恒的爱 ♪
♪ We all spent the night together ♪
♪ 我们一起度过了一夜 ♪
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
let's go.
我们走吧。
♪ Unchanged ♪
♪ 不变 ♪
♪ A predestined relationship ♪
♪ 有缘份 ♪
♪ But roles that shouldn't always be ♪
♪ 但不应该总是这样的角色 ♪
♪ Unlimited Patience ♪
♪ 无限的耐心 ♪
♪ Wishing to escape this conflict ♪
♪ 希望逃离这场冲突 ♪
♪ The mutual trust we have ♪
♪ 我们之间的相互信任 ♪
♪ To cut resentment and hatred. ♪
♪ 减少怨恨和仇恨。♪
♪ This colorful array in the sky ♪
♪ 天空中的彩色阵列 ♪
♪ Just you and me ♪
♪ 只有你和我 ♪
♪ You are the beginning of anticipation ♪
♪ 你是期待的开始 ♪
♪ Heartbroken ♪
♪ 心碎 ♪
♪ You are the final answer ♪
♪ 你就是最终的答案 ♪
♪ I don't regret it, I don't regret it ♪
♪ 我不后悔，我不后悔 ♪
♪ My unspoken words are written on parchment ♪
♪ 我未说出口的话 都写在羊皮纸上 ♪
♪ Imitators who follow one after the other ♪
♪ 纷纷效仿的模仿者 ♪
♪ You are the only one ♪
♪ 你是唯一的 ♪
♪ The heart knows in secret ♪
♪ 心秘密地知道 ♪
♪ You are a persistent longing ♪
♪ 你是一种执着的渴望 ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ 永远 ♪
♪ I'm willing to leave this world for you ♪ ♪ I want to leave this world for you ♪
♪ 我愿意为你离开这个世界 ♪ ♪ 我想为你离开这个世界 ♪
♪ I have no regrets in this life ♪
♪ 此生无悔 ♪
♪ You are the beginning of anticipation ♪
♪ 你是期待的开始 ♪
♪ Heartbroken ♪
♪ 心碎 ♪
♪ You are the final answer ♪
♪ 你就是最终的答案 ♪
♪ I don't regret it, I don't regret it ♪
♪ 我不后悔，我不后悔 ♪
♪ My unspoken words are written on parchment ♪
♪ 我未说出口的话 都写在羊皮纸上 ♪
♪ Imitators who follow one after the other ♪
♪ 纷纷效仿的模仿者 ♪
♪ You are the only one ♪
♪ 你是唯一的 ♪
♪ The heart knows ♪
♪ 心知道 ♪
♪ You are the eternal longing ♪
♪ 你是永恒的渴望 ♪
♪ I will never back down ♪
♪ 我绝不会退缩 ♪
♪ Never apart no matter what ♪
♪ 无论如何都不要分开 ♪
Heaven and earth can testify to our love. Witness our love.
天地可以见证我们的爱情。 见证我们的爱情。